aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Where are you, En?
어디 있어, 엔?!
En!
엔…!
En.
엔…
En!
엔!
En.
엔…!
That's...
저건!
To Our Future...
우리 미래로…
I see.
그렇구나…
I had no clue.
단서는… 없었구나
I'll give En a severe warning when he comes back.
엔 녀석, 돌아오면 엄중 주의다!
Right! How come he can't contact us at all?
맞아! 어떻게 연락 한 통도 없냐!
His transmitter must be broken!
통신기가 고장난 거예요, 분명…
Ms. Maria. He'll be alright. No need to worry!
마리아 씨 엔이라면 괜찮을 겁니다 걱정하실 필요 없어요
Right! I'll go look for him one more time!
그래! 제가 한 번 더 찾아보고 오겠습니다
It's Rai.
라이다…
Dag Fire's armor.
다그 파이어의… 장갑이야
He was been blown into space by that huge explosion.
그 대폭발로 우주까지 날아간 거예요
It was spinning around the orbit.
궤도 위를 맴돌고 있었습니다
What about En...
그래서 엔은…
Where is En?!
엔은 어딨어?!
I could find nothing more than this.
발견한 건 이것 뿐입니다
Maybe... En senpai is at...
설마… 어쩌면 엔 선배는…
So what!
그게 뭐 어쨌다고!
Nothing...
그런…
Such a piece means nothing by itself!
그런 파편이 발견됐다고 해서 대체 뭐가 어쨌다는 거야?!
Maria...
마리아…
Say something, and don't remain quiet!
가만히 있지 말고 뭐라고 말 좀 해봐!
Hey, Kai!
응, 카이?!
En isn't dead.
엔은 안 죽었어…
En isn't dead!
엔은 안 죽었다구!
Ms. Maria!
마리아 씨!
You idiot! This is your fault for bringing something evasive like this!
이 멍청아! 네가 어정쩡하게 이딴 걸 줏어와서 그렇잖아!
No way...
그럴 수가…
Let's see... Next week on Saturday, at noon!
그러니까… 다음주 토요일 낮 12시
The place will be... Ah.
장소는… 그래
In front of the bank with a big clock near Sankai bridge.
산카이 다리 근처에 있는 대형 시계가 있는 은행 앞
Right! When you pay me the debt on Saturday, buy me a meal.
맞아! 돈 갚는 김에 밥도 사줘
And movies and karaoke too!
그리고나서 영화랑 노래방도!
Principal...
교장 선생님…
What's wrong, Tobe?
왜 그러나, 토베 양
En's not here.
엔이… 없어요
He promised to meet me today...
오늘 걔랑 만나기로 약속했는데…
He's not there.
없어요
Is it about a date?
데이트 약속인 겐가?
(瀬をはやみ 岩にせかるる 滝川の われても末に あはむとぞ思ふ)
A stream speeds up to a slant, and divides by a rock, but join into one at last.
흐르는 물은 경사면에서 속도가 붙고 바위로 둘로 나뉘지만 결국엔 만난다.
Likewise, I wish to meet you again, even if we have to separate for now.
그처럼, 지금은 갈라지더라도 다시 만나길 바란다.
If you promised, then please wait at the place you promised to meet.
약속했다면 약속 장소에서 그를 기다리게
He does as he pleases most of the time, but Daidouji is a man who keeps his word.
다소 다이도우지는 약속은 지키는 남자라네
Don't you agree?
안 그런가?
Yes!
네!
Daidouji...
다이도우지…
En was a Dagwon...
엔 녀석이 다그온이었다니…
Look up, Gaku.
얼굴 들어라, 가쿠
What? It's Geki.
뭐야, 게키잖아
Is "what" a greeting?
"뭐야"가 인사냐?
I guess you were crying!
너 질질 짜고 있었구만?
I wasn't crying!
안 울었어!
I, Geki Kuroiwa, will fix your weak guts!
이 쿠로이와 게키가 네녀석의 나약한 근성을 고쳐주마!
Leave me alone! I'm not in the mood to play at the moment.
내버려 둬 난 지금 놀 기분 아니야
Here it goes!
으랏차!
The crybaby sure flies away well!
울보라 그런지 잘 날아가는구만!
What's that for, Geki?!
무슨 짓이야, 게키?!
Oh, I didn't know a crybaby could become angry properly!
호오, 울보도 제대로 화 내는구만?
What?!
뭐야?!
If you feel mortified, then try taking me down!
분하면 날 쓰러뜨려 봐라!
Crybaby Gaku! Coward Gaku!
울보 가쿠~ 겁쟁이 가쿠~
You bastard!
이자식!
Don't call me names!
가쿠 가쿠 하지마--!
You know, En isn't dead!
엔은 말이다! 엔은 안 죽었어!
En will definitely come back!
녀석은 반드시 돌아올 거다!
He and I promised!
나와 녀석은 약속했다!
To postpone the duel until we take down Sargasso!
사르갓소를 전멸시킬 때까지 결투는 미루기로 말이다!
He broke my left arm! It's my turn to break his!
녀석은 내 왼팔을 부러뜨렸어! 이번엔 내가 녀석의 팔을 꺾어버릴 차례야!
So...
그러니까…
So...!
그러니까…!
How's that?!
맛이 어떠냐!
En, you idiot!
엔, 이 바보녀석!
Geki...
게키…
Don't cry, Geki. En will come back. Definitely!
울지마, 게키 엔은 돌아올 거야 반드시!
One hour left.
한시간 남았구나
The game is boring without him.
게임 참 재미없군
Hey!
어머?
Sawamura?
사·와·무·라 군?
I didn't think Erika would ask me out for a date!
설마 에리카가 나에게 데이트 신청을 할 줄이야~
I didn't ask you for a date...
그다지 데이트 신청을 한 건…
Could it be... am I dreaming at all? Is it all a dream?
혹시 나, 꿈을 꾸고 있을 리는 없구나;;
Nope, it definitely isn't! It's a reality! Real!
음, 확실히 꿈이 아니야! 현실이야, 현실!
Hey, Sawamura?
저기, 사와무라 군…
I know, I know! A true love does not require words!
다 알아, 다 알아~ 사랑에 말은 필요없지
I see through what's in Erika's mind!
에리카의 마음은 다 꿰뚫어보고 있다우
-Sawamura?
-What should we do now?
-사와무라 군…
-이제부터 뭐 할까?
Let's go anywhere and play!
어디든 가서 놀아보자구!
Sawamura!
사와무라 군!
What's up?
대체 왜 그래?
Nothing...
뭐가…
You don't look like you're having fun at all. You're faking yourself.
왠지 전혀 안 즐거워 보여 엄청 무리하고 있잖아
I'm... having fun...
난… 즐거워…
Today's Sawamura isn't like the you that I know.
오늘의 사와무라 군… 사와무라 군답지 않아
Sorry.
미안해…
I apologize if I hurt your feelings.
기분 상했다면 사과할게
Get a grip!
기운 내!
기운 내라구!
Erika...
에리카…
Noon...
12시…
Take that for me.
내려줘
Very well.
알았어
-Here.
-Thank you!
-자
-고마워
He's late again.
그녀석, 또 지각인가…
I thought about it...
나, 문득 생각해 봤는데…
Maybe Brave Seijin didn't choose you without any reason. It's not by chance.
브레이브 성인이 너희들을 다그온으로 선택한 것 우연이 아니었을지도…
Why?
어째서?
Looking at you guys, I just feel it.
너희들을 보고 있으면 그런 느낌이 들어
Everyone really likes En.
모두들 엔을 정말 좋아하고 말이야
That's not true!
그건 아니야!
While I don't know how others think, I hate En.
다른 애들은 몰라도 난 엔을 싫어해!
Kai?
카이…?
He is casually late at school!
학교엔 거리낌없이 지각
He eats bento and even sleeps during class.
수업중에 도시락을 까먹고 졸기까지 해!
He ignores the warnings about discipline, and doesn't know how to behave toward his superiors!
풍기위원의 주의를 무시하고 윗사람에 대한 예의도 몰라!
Just like back then.
그 때도 그랬어
When the alien invasion began, he was supposed to be grounded at his home but he went to an arcade!
우주인의 침략이 시작된 그날 녀석은 자택 근신의 몸이면서도 오락실에 갔어!
Grounded?
자택 근신?
He injured Geki in a fight.
싸움으로 게키에게 부상을 입혔어
He truly is...
정말 녀석은…
Rough! Single-celled! Frivolous! Shallow!
거칠고…! 단세포에…! 경박하고…! 촐랑대고…!
Really! Really makes me worried...
정말! 정말 속썩이는…
He's a younger brother that makes you worried, right?
속썩이는 "동생"이지?
Luna, I'm sorry, but can you leave me alone?
루나… 미안하지만 날 혼자 있게 해 주지 않을래?
Yes.
알았어
En...
엔…
Alive...
살아…
Please be alive...
살아 있어다오…!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Hey, sister! Let's play!
거기 아가씨, 같이 놀자구
Did your boyfriend dump you?
어차피 남자친구한테 퇴짜맞았잖아?
Have a drive with us!
우리랑 드라이브 하자구~
Spirit Dispersal!
원령 퇴산!
(怨靈退散)
He- hey!
이, 이봐!
-This brat looks dangerous!
-Let's go find someone else!
-이년 위험해!
-다른 애 찾아보자!
En, you idiot!
엔, 이 바보!
If you don't come back in next 30 minutes, I'll go back!
30분 후까지 안오면 돌아갈 거야!
Aren't you cold?
춥지 않니?
Not at all.
아무렇지도 않아
The air is good!
공기 참 좋다~
Your dream was right again.
또 너의 꿈이 들어맞았구나
You told me before. You dreamed about you and I climbing mountain.
얼마 전에 말했잖니 나와 산에 오르는 꿈을 꿨다고
You remembered!
기억하고 있었구나
It's great that the doctor allowed you to come out.
의사 선생님께서 허락해 주셔서 다행이야
Thank you, brother.
고마워, 오빠
It's because Minako did great.
미나코가 힘내서 그런 거야
Your doctor was surprised too.
선생님도 놀라셨더라
I want to be discharged soon.
어서 퇴원하고 싶다
By the way, Minako.
그런데 말이야, 미나코
Huh?
응?
Did you dream this morning?
오늘 아침 꿈 꾸지 않았니?
Of someone...
누군가의…
Dream?
꿈?
Your dreams are always right. So...
네 꿈은 항상 들어맞잖아 그러니까…
Not today.
안 꿨어
But who are you talking about?
근데, 누구 이야기야?
A close friend.
친한 친구야
Close friend?
친한 친구?
We can be here without any worry, thanks to him.
나와 네가 이렇게 있을 수 있는 것도 그녀석 덕분이야
That tree... the ocean... the sky...
저 나무를…
바다를… 하늘을…
This Earth...
이 지구를…
He's the one who protected it!
지켜낸 남자야!
Awesome!
대단해~
Did you do all of these by yourself?
이걸 전부 요쿠 선배 혼자서?
This is so awesome!
대단합니다!
I collected these samples to surprise my everyone when we take down all the aliens of Sargasso.
이 표본은 사르갓소의 우주인을 전멸시키면 애들에게 보여줘서 놀래키려고 모은 거예요
I'm surprised!
놀랐습니다
This is more than what the Space Police did!
우주 경찰 기구도 무색해질 정도예요
But this thing...
하지만, 이딴 거…
It was a short time, but I am happy to know that I could work with you senpais.
짧은 기간이었지만 선배들과 함께 일을 할 수 있어서 정말 다행입니다
I hope En senpai is safe.
무사하겠죠, 엔 선배…
It's useless!
아무런 의미도 없어!
Yoku senpai...
요쿠 선배…
No matter how many of these things I collect, if En doesn't come back, they are all useless!
이딴 걸 아무리 많이 모았다고 해도 엔이 돌아오질 않으면 의미가 없단 말이야!
You're late!
늦었잖아~
Sorry, sorry! Let's go.
미안 미안, 가자
It's snowing...
눈…
Here.
자
What's that?!
뭐야!
You hit me first!
네놈이 먼저 쳤잖아!
Yo! Occult girl!
여어, 오컬트 소녀
I'm... late again, ain't I?
또… 지각해 버렸네
En...
엔…
Sorry to keep you waiting.
기다리게 해서 미안해
I guess the theaters are closed by now.
영화관… 닫았겠지?
En...
엔…
I wonder if any karaokes are open.
노래방은 열었을라나?
En!
엔…
엔---!
Maria...
마리아…!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
By chance, we are given a quiet afternoon
우연이 준 조용한 오후에
Pick a gently connected hill
완만하게 이어진 언덕을 골라
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다를 만나러 갔지
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
My shoelaces came undone, so I tied them again
풀린 신발 끈도 다시 묶고
I make sure of this wondrous age!
신비한 이 시대를 확인하고 있어
How embarrassing this "youth" is
「청춘이다」란 말이 쑥스러운 건
Maybe that's because it's actually real
아마도 그게 사실이라서겠지
Someday, the fragments of my worries will fade
고민의 조각들은 어느덧
away into the horizon
수평선 너머로 사라져갈 테니
You just have to live the current moment straight on
정직하게 지금을 살아가면 돼
I will not lose sight of any of my dreams
꿈이 있는 곳을 놓치지 않을 거야
It reflects my feelings
마음을 비추는
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Right!
맞다!
This too!
이녀석도…
You can have that.
그건 가져도 괜찮아
Luna senpai! Time to set off!
루나 선배! 출발 시간입니다!
See you again.
또 만나자
Yes, sir!
네!
En!
엔~
Let's go, leader!
가자, 리더!
Alright!
좋았어!
Let's go!
가자~!
The End
끝